It was an age of war.
Relying on only his own skill...
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man is not
a wondering samurai of today.
I don't feel comfortable wearing these.
The doctor told you
to protect against cataracts.
I don't need them
to go to the stationery store.
No. Put them on.
Don't worry, they look good on you.
That laugh...
She thinks I look silly.
I wonder if I look shady.
Or pretending to be a celebrity?
Or perhaps like a crazy senior citizen
who is way too into rock music?
I'm worrying too much.
TAKESHI KASUMI
Such a smooth write.
-How is it?
-Very nice.
Wow, $200?
You look like a professional writer
with that pen.
I went over budget.
I was trying to look good
and couldn't say no.
It's a bad habit.
Good thing I wore these.
Italian?
A beer and some pizza would be great
on a bright, sunny day like this.
All right!
Italian for lunch it is!
After retiring, he lost his title
as a corporate man
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story
is about a normal 60-year-old man...
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
PASTA THE SAMURAI WAY
I thought it was going
to be a more casual place.
Here you are, sir.
This is our menu.
A course menu...
Fifty bucks for lunch?
I made a mistake coming here.
Are you ready to order?
The pasta course, please.
Understood.
Would you like a drink?
Beer to start!
Right away.
What have I done?!
"Beer to start"?
This isn't some pub.
They must think I'm an unrefined old man.
Here you are, sir.
-May I pour it for you?
-Yes, please.
Tastes great!
Nothing beats a cold beer on a hot day.
This is our house-baked bread.
Please try it with olive oil
and balsamic vinegar.
Balsamic?
The acidity is just right!
This is different and fun.
Welcome.
I'm Nakanishi.
We have your table.
What about this bread?
It's good.
So, this is Italian food too?
The blue-crab spaghetti here
is delectable.
Really? I love crab!
-So distasteful.
-It's too much.
I can't believe it.
Indeed.
Right?
Did I do something wrong?
That's it.
I forgot!
I really screwed up.
A major faux pas.
Yes?
Some white wine, please.
What label?
Yes...
May we see the list?
Wine?
Oh, now I see.
To order a beer at a place like this,
is like being uncultured.
I lost a point with that move.
But this one is worse.
That's three points lost.
Any more mistakes, and I'll be given
a red card and thrown out.
Here you are, sir.
Pardon my reach.
Potato and snow-crab terrine
with a crab bagna càuda sauce,
topped with an herb salad,
sourced from a farm.
What'd he say?
I couldn't catch a word.
I really don't like all this formality.
It's like potato salad.
I think he said crab sauce.
I was right.
Potato salad and crab sauce...
can be made at home.
No need to go out to a restaurant.
Today's soup is
a yellow bell pepper cold soup.
Enjoy.
What kind of soup?
I was distracted
by this UFO saucer of a plate...
and didn't hear a word.
I know the rules.
No noise allowed.
Oops.
This is good!
I don't know what it is, but it's great.
Eating too quickly is also rude.
I can't help it if I'm thought
to be a grown man who lacks...
refinement and manners.
This is wearing me out.
Apologies for the wait.
Here you are.
Vegetable and mozzarella spaghettini
with tomato sauce.
I need a tape recorder
to remember all that.
I'll definitely get thrown out
if I slurp these noodles.
Although, in Japan,
it's considered appropriate
to slurp noodles.
I'm bound up by all this etiquette.
I can't even move.
Sir, you must eat with proper manners.
What's this?
He's hopeless.
Truly disgusting.
Indeed, the food...
is delicious!
But you'll ruin the flavor with
all your petty talk.
No?
It's because you're always doing that!
Excuse me.
Yes?
Chopsticks, please.
-Yes, sir.
-And more bread, please.
Understood.
Delicious.
The tomato flavor is exquisite.
This is mozzarella cheese.
It goes good with the tomato.
Indeed, the food here is delicious.
If I can't eat the way I want,
what's the point?
I was about to ruining this great food.
In the end...
I was the one being paranoid
about everything.
It's a nice place.
Maybe next time...
I'll bring her here.
I'm back.
Welcome home.
That laugh!
What?
Before I left today,
you looked at me and said,
they look good, but you laughed.
So?
They really look good?
I told you. They look good on you.
You weren't making fun of me?
You're being paranoid.
Oh, okay.
It's just...
I thought you looked
like a friendly mobster.
So... is that good, or bad?
Subtitle translation by
Jeffrey Hales